Buckle up.
Saving Bikini Bottom: The Sandy Cheeks Movie is a family,
comedy, adventure film directed by Liza Johnson.
When Bikini Bottom is scooped from the ocean, scientific squirrel Sandy Cheeks and
her pal SpongeBob SquarePants saddle up for Texas to save their town.
Sandy / Bottomite Crowd (voice), played by Carolyn Lawrence.
SpongeBob / Gary / Sonny / Various (voice), played by Tom Kenny.
Mr. Krabs / Clyde / Neighbor #1 / Bottomite #2 /
Bottomite Crowd (voice), played by Clancy Brown.
Patrick / Bottomite #4 / Bottomite Crowd (voice), played by Bill Fagerbakke.
Fred / Larry / Plankton / Video Announcer / Plankton Lincoln / Snail
Walker / Bottomite Crowd (voice), played by Mr. Lawrence.
Squidward / Butch / Police Loudspeaker / Bottomite #1 /
Bottomite Crowd (voice), played by Rodger Bumpass.
Saving Bikini Bottom: The Sandy Cheeks Movie is a 2024 American adventure comedy film based on the
animated television series SpongeBob SquarePants, created by Stephen Hillenburg.
It was directed by Liza Johnson and written by Tom
Stern and Kaz, based on a story by Kaz.
Combining CGI animation with live-action, the film stars the series' regular voice cast and introduces new characters performed
by Johnny Knoxville, Craig Robinson, Grey DeLisle, Ilia Isorelýs Paulino, Matty Cardarople, and Wanda Sykes.
The plot follows Sandy and SpongeBob as they venture to Sandy's home
state of Texas to save Bikini Bottom from an evil CEO.
It is the first entry in a series of SpongeBob character spin-off films
for Netflix, followed by Plankton: The Movie in 2025.
The film was first conceived during a pitching session for ideas
for The SpongeBob Movie: Sponge on the Run (2020).
In March 2020, ViacomCBS announced that it would be producing
SpongeBob spin-off films for streaming television.
In May 2021, a spin-off film starring Sandy was
announced, with Johnson, Kaz, and Stern attached.
Moniker composed the original score.
Prior to its release, the film was leaked on January
21, 2024, as a video upload on X.
Saving Bikini Bottom: The Sandy Cheeks Movie was
officially released on Netflix on August 2, 2024.
The film debuted with 12.8 million views during its premiere weekend, making it Netflix's
most-watched title of the week and received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of squirrel, texas, road
trip, save the day, based on tv series.
The tone is lighthearted.